lavaplace.com 2016-05-31

# Privacy & Use Policy

### Privacy and Use Policy

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us through our [website](https://www.lavaplace.com/?page=support) or by sending an email to info [at] lavaplace.com, or by phone (+370.68961278), or write to us at 

Privacy Matters  
UAB NEOTEKA  
Draugystes 29-4  
LT-31221 Visaginas  
Lithuania  

Through lavaplace.com, our members may take advantage of the many services and features available online. In order to provide you with our services, you must provide us with certain necessary information. Lava Place treats all of your information with the utmost care for your privacy and security. Lava Place does not sell, trade, or otherwise disclose customer lists or information to unaffiliated third parties without your permission. In the event that Lava Place should be acquired or substantially all of its assets transferred, customer information would be considered a transferable asset. Lava Place will give registered members notice prior to transferring their information, and an opportunity to opt-out of having their information transferred to the new entity. Further, in the event we make a material change in the way we collect your personal information, use your personal information, or change our email policies, you will be notified by email or through a prominent notice on our website. For your information, below is a detailed list of the services available through lavaplace.com, an outline of the information collected from you to provide such services, and a description of what we do with such information. 

Certain features of our website, including the Lava Place compatibility questionnaire and personality profile, require the client or website user to sign up before accessing those services. During sign-up, lavaplace.com collects the following information: name, address, birth date, and email address, along with other information about you and the type of people and relationships you are seeking through our website (e.g., hobbies, interests, personal preferences, personality traits). This information may then be imported into the website programs to simplify the amount of information you will be required to enter when using the features available on lavaplace.com. In the event there is a change or update to the services available on our website, Lava Place may use your information to contact you regarding such a change or update. Your demographic data is used to show you content that may be of interest to you, and to help us display the content of our website according to your preferences.

Also, Lava Place uses your sign-up information to send you information about our company. You may opt out of receiving such information; see the choice/opt-out section below. 

If you use a chat room on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. It is important for you to exercise discretion and appropriate caution when deciding, if at all, to reveal personal information in these areas. Users who violate chat room rules, may be temporarily or permanently banned from accessing our chat rooms and/or our website at any time in our sole discretion.

When you initially provide your financial information on lavaplace.com, we use that data to bill you for products and services you use, as well as check your qualifications. If you choose to participate in any discount, rebate or other incentive programs, your financial information disclosure enables your participation as well. By making a purchase on the website, or accessing any financial transaction or activity on the website, you automatically consent to allowing us to provide your financial information to our service providers, as well as your credit card issuer for their assistance in processing your transaction. Your financial activity on the website also allows us to contact any other third parties we determine as necessary to process your transactions. These third parties may include banking facilities and/or credit card institutions used to process and verify your financial transaction. It is also important to note that occasionally separate third parties offer products and services on the website, and/or administer programs offered on the website. In those cases, if you purchase, register or make reservations for these products or services offered by the third parties, or participate in programs that are administered by third parties, any financial information you submit is passed by us through the website to those third parties with your full consent, implied by your consent and participation. 

Additionally, if you submit information on a Co-Branded page, or you accessed the page on which you submitted information by clicking a link on a Co-Branded page, then we may share your financial information with that associated Co-Branded company. Any of these various third parties mentioned above (including Co-Branded companies) may be authorized to use your financial information in accordance with our contractual arrangements with such third parties. The usage of this financial information must also be in accordance with their privacy policies, over which we have no control. Because of this, you agree that we are not responsible or liable for any of their actions or omissions. Additionally, you agree that we may use and disclose all such information so submitted to such third parties in the same manner in which we are entitled to use and disclose any other information that you submit to us. 

These other "Co-Branded" websites are managed by the companies providing the services. Any information you provide on these websites is governed by each website's own privacy policy, or the privacy policy of the company providing the services. Because lavaplace.com is not responsible for the privacy practices of these companies, the content of their websites, or the services offered through these Co-Branded websites, we recommend that you review the privacy policies of these websites for information about their respective privacy practices. This section will be updated periodically as Lava Place expands to offer exciting new services through the use of co-branded websites. 

Users of lavaplace.com should note that when you are on lavaplace.com, you may be directed to other websites that are beyond our control. For example, if you click on a banner advertisement, the click may take you off the lavaplace.com website. Banner advertisers on lavaplace.com do not have access to your personally identifiable information so long as you remain on our website. However, these other websites may independently collect data, solicit personal information or send their own cookies to you in accordance with their own policies. Lava Place, or its affiliates, is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. We strongly encourage you to review the policies of any such third parties to whom you may give personally identifiable information. We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf. In order to make sure that the advertising you may see is relevant to you, these companies may employ cookies and action tags, also known as single-pixel gifs or Web beacons. Be assured that any information these third parties collect is completely anonymous. If you do not want these third-party advertisers collecting information about you, [ click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp) to opt out. 

Cookies are used to deliver content specific to a user's potential interests and for the administration of passwords, among other purposes. For example, we also may use cookies to ensure users do not see the same advertisements and product offerings repeatedly. It is important to note that cookies are not linked to personally identifiable information. Since our website is specifically designed to your interests, disabling your browser from accepting cookies will prevent you from accessing many of the features on lavaplace.com. 

A user's IP address is used by most e-commerce websites to collect demographic data and improve service. We use your IP address, as well as the website you visited prior to our website for much the same purpose. We automatically gather this information after each visit and translate this information into a resource that we can use to identify and correct problems with our website and better understand our users, as well as continually update and expand our offerings. 

Lava Place guards your personal information carefully. The individually identifiable information that you provide will be used by Lava Place and its affiliated companies to provide you with information about products and services available to you through Lava Place, its affiliated companies, and/or non-affiliated third parties. Lava Place will not disclose individually identifiable information to non-affiliated third parties without your permission. You may opt-out of sharing your personal information with affiliated companies by contacing our [Cusstomer Care](https://www.lavaplace.com/?page=support)

Upon your request, lavaplace.com will share your information with its affiliated representatives. For example, if you need assistance in completing your profile, you may request that an affiliated relationship consultant contact you to review your profile or provide other assistance. Upon such a request, lavaplace.com will forward your name, phone number and other information you authorize to a relationship consultant. Lava Place will not, however, forward any information without your request to do so.

Lava Place may share aggregate information collected through lavaplace.com with non-affiliated third parties. Aggregate information does not identify you, but rather is based upon a summary of information about all users. For example, we may tell an advertiser that 100,000 users clicked on a specific link, and out of the 100,000 users, 85% were from Texas. This aggregate information assists advertisers in determining how they can best promote their products. We will not tell our advertisers who it was that saw or clicked on their advertisements.

Lava Place will not disclose your personally identifiable information to non-affiliated third parties without your permission unless we need to do so in order to comply with applicable law, a subpoena, or other legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. Lava Place does not sell or rent individually identifiable information about its users to non-affiliated third parties. If Lava Place intends to share your personal information with a non-affiliated third party, we will do so only with your knowledge and consent.

Lava Place recognizes how important and sensitive data is, and that is why we have implemented policies and procedures to preserve the security of your information. While Lava Place strives to protect the information you provide through lavaplace.com, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your information, Lava Place cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to or receive from us through our website and online services. lavaplace.com operates secure data networks that are password-protected and are not available to the public. 

Lava Place reviews its security policies regarding lavaplace.com on a regular basis, and changes are made as necessary. Only a select group of authorized individuals within Lava Place have access to user information. 

Lava Place recognizes how important it is for you to have access to your information at any time. We have implemented a policy specific to information availability. Our network will be made available 99% of the time, excluding time for maintenance, backup and other routine services. In the event of a disaster or other prolonged service interruption, access to system information and other resources will be limited until any problem is corrected. Should you believe that we are not following our availability policy, please contact our [Customer Care](https://www.lavaplace.com/?page=support). 

Lava Place also understands that your circumstances and preferences change. That is why we have simplified the process of amending, updating or deleting your information. 

Your lavaplace.com account information is password protected so that only you have access to this personal information. You may update this information as necessary by clicking on the appropriate edit option in the My Profile section, which allows you to access and edit your account information, including your opt-in/opt-out choices. 

We strongly recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Lava Place will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or email. Also, remember to log out of your lavaplace.com account and close your browser window when you have finished your session. This will help to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place. 

If you change your mind about receiving special promotions and other information from Lava Place, simply log into lavaplace.com, click "Account Settings" and delete the check mark(s) from the various correspondence options. You may also opt-out of receiving special promotions and other information from Lava Place by following the unsubscribe instructions at the end of the applicable promotional email(s) or by sending an email to info [at] lavaplace dot com

Last updated on April 19, 2011.
